"超感神探" 前情提要...
Previously on "The Mentalist"...
十年前 人称红约翰的连环杀手
Ten years ago, the serial killer known as Red John
杀害了我的妻子和女儿
killed my wife and daughter.
从此我们一刻不停地对其进行搜捕
We've been hunting for him ever since.
我们自称"布雷克组织"
We call ourselves the Blake Association.
组织里还有什么人?
Well, who else is in the association?
警察 法官 联邦调查局探员...
Cops, judges, FBI Agents...
任何在执法体系中有事要瞒的人
Anyone in law enforcement that needs a secret covered up.
一个坏警察构成的秘密组织
A secret society of dirty cops.
红约翰是其中一员
And Red John's a member.
Kira Tinsley死前告诉了我一件事
Kira Tinsley told me something before she passed.
她说凶手... 红约翰...
She told me that her killer... Red John...
有个文身...
has a tattoo...
左肩上三个点
Three dots on his left arm.
那红约翰是谁呢?
So who's Red John?
时至今日 我们很欣慰地宣布
Today we're pleased to announce
我们... 我们终于确认了他的名字 他的长相
that we... we finally have a name, a face.
加州调查局的局长
The Director of the division of law enforcement,
Gail Bertram 就是红约翰
Gail bertram, is Red John.
我手里的是
I am holding in my hand a writ
联邦法官起草的书面命令
from a federal judge.
联邦调查局将关闭你们的部门
The FBI Is closing down your organization right now.
我们没戏了 没什么好做的了
We're done. There's nothing more to do here.
你不能就这么放弃 我不相信
You're not quitting. I don't believe it.
事情已经不归我们管了
It's out of our hands for now.
我会和你联系的 好吗?
I'll be in touch. Okay?
抱歉 为过去的一切
I'm sorry. For everything.
--==圣城家园SCG字幕组 http://hd.cnscg.com/==--
仅供翻译交流使用, 禁止用于商业用途
协调：有个饭团
时间轴：pisces夜
翻译：波特妹子 Red Shadow 捞小盐
校对：Red Shadow
Lisbon啊
Lisbon.
很开心你加入我们
Glad you can join us.
- 堵车了  - 嗯 Jane在哪?
- Traffic.  - Hmm. Where's Jane?
他有空了就来见你
He'll be in to see you as soon as he's able.
这边请
This way.
请坐
Please, take a seat.
天 真是一团糟 对吧?
Boy, this is a mess, huh?
非常糟糕
A big mess.
- 是这样 我觉得我们...  - 你一会儿再说
- Look, I think we all...  - You can talk later.
我理解...
Now I understand...
你们肯定都很害怕
You must all feel scared,
紧张
nervous.
不知道接下来会发生什么 对吧?
Don't know what in the hell is gonna happen next, right?
- 探员...  - 容我解释接下来的事
- Agent...  - So let me explain what's next.
接下来几天
Over the next few days,
我们会单独与你们每个人...
we will be talking to each of you...
谈话
individually.
你们有权带一位律师
You are entitled to bring along an attorney
或工会代表 随你们选择
or a union rep, should you so choose.
我们为什么需要律师?
Why would we need an attorney?
这要从我们的立场看问题了 Kimball
Well, let's look at this from our perspective, Kimball.
你们的局长Bertram是罪犯
Your boss Bertram is a criminal.
说你们有嫌疑也不为过
Makes sense that you might be one, too.
我们会密切注意你们所有人
We will be looking very closely at all of you.
如果你们做过任何事
If you have ever done anything
即使与此事不沾边
even remotely questionable,
我们也会找出来
we will find out,
并且起诉
and we will prosecute.
当然 除非
Unless, of course,
我们非常满意你们的配合
we feel very, very comfortable with your cooperation.
那样你们可以有回旋空间
Then you got a little wiggle room.
加利福尼亚 萨克拉门托 弗兰克林区
联邦调查局在进行
The FBI is overseeing
一场国际性的追捕
an international manhunt
寻找萨克拉门托执法人员
for prominent Sacramento law enforcement official
也就是Gail Bertram
Gail Bertram.
联邦调查局人员确定Bertram
FBI sources confirm that Bertram
就是臭名昭著的连环杀手红约翰
is believed to be the notorious serial killer Red John,
因在加利福尼亚中心地带施行一系列
wanted for a string of grisly murders
残忍凶杀案被通缉
across the California heartland.
嘿 伙计
Hey, man.
生意如何?
How's it going?
有公用电话吗?
Do you have a pay phone?
就在后面
It's right back there.
谢谢
Thank you.
嘿 Ali 近来如何? 呃 来张六选一彩票...
Hey, Ali, how you doing? Uh, give me a pick 6...
再来一盒菠萝雪茄烟
and one of those pineapple cheroots.
六选一彩票 方头雪茄烟
Pick 6. Cheroot.
喂?
Hello?
你好 Patrick
Hello, Patrick.
我不用伪装声音吧?
I don't have to use a funny voice, do I?
你知道我是谁
You know who this is.
我的确知道
Yes, I do.
很奇怪吧?
It's weird, huh?
因为我们最后一次...
'Cause the last time we...
举起手来...
Put your hands up...
喂?
Hello?
- 喂?  - 谢谢
- Hello?  - Thanks.
不客气
No problem.
喂? Bertram? 喂?
Hello? Bertram? Hello?
超感神探 第六季第8集
没人 长官
Clear, sir.
可不是
No kidding.
他在哪?
Where is he?
如果你问的是Jane 我不知道
If you're asking about Jane, I don't know.
- 哼  - 你看过楼上了吗?
- Hmm.  - Did you check upstairs?
看过了
Yeah.
或许你没听说
You know, maybe you haven't heard.
大约一小时前 Gail Bertram
About an hour ago, Gail Bertram
在萨克拉门托东部的加油站杀了一名警察
killed a cop at a gas station in east Sac.
我听说了
I heard.
那你知道Bertram在加油站干嘛吗?
Did you hear what Bertram was doing at the gas station?
不知道
No.
用公用电话
Using a pay phone.
猜猜他给谁打电话呢
Guess who he was calling.
我猜是Jane
I'm gonna guess Jane.
没错 那他在哪?
Ahh. Yeah. So where is he?
我不知道
I don't know.
我想你知道
I think you do.
我管不了你想什么
I can't help what you think.
我想你的男朋友在勾结
I think your boyfriend is colluding
一名危险逃犯
with a dangerous fugitive.
我想他已经深陷
I think he is up to his neck
这场"布雷克组织"的臆想之中
in this Blake Association craziness,
或许你也是
and probably you are, too.
我没有 他也没有
I'm not. He's not.
Jane管不了谁给他电话
Jane can't help who calls him,
他也不是我男朋友
and he's not my boyfriend.
太可惜了 Teresa
It's a damn shame, Teresa.
大家都说...
By all accounts...
你曾是个好警察
uou were a good cop.
我仍然是
I still am.
嘿 头儿!
Hey, boss!
Rigsby吗?
Rigsby?
外面安全吗?
Is it safe?
嗯 你在干吗?
Yeah. What are you doing?
我们听说Bertram今早的所为了
We heard about what Bertram did this morning.
听说联邦调查局在找我们
We heard the FBI were looking for us.
所以呢? 你们就躲在停车场里?
So what now? You're hiding in the parking lot?
不是 我们没有躲 我们只是... 低调行事
No. No, we're not hiding. We're just... laying low.
我们暂时是安全的 目前还没有
Well, we're safe for now. There's no arrest warrant
对我们的逮捕令
that's put out for us just yet.
早晚会有的
Give 'em time.
Jane在哪?
Where's Jane?
别问
Don't ask.
她已经问了
She just did.
听我说
Listen to me.
加州调查局现在解散了
The CBI is gone now.
我们只能靠自己 你们要保护好自己
We're on our own. You need to protect yourselves.
你们不知道Jane在哪 不知道他在做什么
You don't know where Jane is, you don't know what he's doing,
而你们也不想知道 懂了吗?
and you don't want to know, you understand?
是 头儿
Yes, boss.
- 是 头儿  - 是 头儿
- Yes, boss.  - Yes, boss.
那就好
All right then.
但我不是你们的头儿了 这正是重点
But I am not your boss anymore. That's the point.
我们孤军奋斗了
We're on our own.
好 明白了
Yeah, we get it.
那他在哪呢?
So where is he?
加利福尼亚 萨克拉门托 威廉地方公园
嘿
Hey.
你被通缉了
You're a wanted man.
我希望如此
Well, I like to think so.
是真的 Abbott真的对你发布了通缉令
Seriously. Abbott put an actual warrant out on you.
呃 又不是第一次了
Eh. It's not the first time.
你是要告诉我 还是怎样?
So you gonna tell me, or what?
是的 呃... Bertram给我电话了
Oh, yeah. Uh... Bertram called me.
- 我知道  - 嗯
- I know.  - Mm.
他说什么了?
What did he say?
不管他想说什么 都没来得及说
Well, whatever he wanted to say, he didn't have time.
他为什么还在这?
Why the hell is he still here?
他想干什么?
What does he want?
我猜他很快会再打电话告诉我的
I'm guessing he'll call back soon and tell me.
你的手机不安全 联邦调查局...
Your phone's not safe. The FBI...
对 他们可以监听电话
Yeah, they have a tap on the line.
但他们还没追踪到我
But they don't have a trace yet.
如果他们追踪到了 那早就逮捕我了
If they had a trace, then I'd be arrested already.
或许吧 但迟早他们会追踪到你的
Maybe so, but sooner or later, they'll get a trace on you.
我知道
I know.
但Bertram来电之前我不能把手机扔了
But I can't get rid of my phone until Bertram calls.
非常让人焦虑不安
It's all very suspenseful.
- 他想干嘛?  - 谁?
- What does he want?  - Who?
- Bertram  - 我们会知道的
- Bertram.  - We'll see.
你这是在含糊其辞了
Now you're being evasive.
鸟儿们的小眼睛真是晶亮如珠
What beady little eyes birds have.
就像小恐龙的眼睛 你知道吗?
Tiny dinosaurs, you know?
我知道
I know.
我知道你知道他想干什么
I know you know what he wants.
他想干什么?
What does he want?
- 喂?  - 抱歉刚刚挂你电话
- Hello?  - Oh, sorry I had to hang up on you.
今天太忙了
It's been a busy day.
没关系 你知道 这手机不安全
Yeah, no problem. You know, this phone is not safe.
我一会回你电话
Let me call you back in a moment.
好
Yeah.
他说什么?
What'd he say?
等一下
Just a second.
嘿 近来如何?
Hey. How you doing?
- 我出100块买你手机  - 什么?
- I'll give you $100 for that phone.  - Huh?
200块买你手机
$200 for that phone.
耍什么花样?
What's the catch?
没花样
No catch.
300块加上...
$300 plus...
替换的手机
a replacement phone.
好吧
Uh, okay.
哥们 一会儿打给你
Dude, I'll call you right back.
很高兴跟你做生意
Pleasure doing business with you.
谢啦 哥们
Thanks, man.
嗯哼
Mm-hmm.
他说什么了?
What did he say?
喂?
Hello?
听着 我们应该见面谈谈
Look, I think we should meet and talk.
- 就我们两个  - 约会吗?
- Just the two of us.  - What, like a date?
呵呵...
Yes...
不是
No.
听着 游戏结束了
Look, the game is over.
我认为是非常精彩的平局
I'd call it a very honorable tie.
既然都结束了
And now that it's over,
我真的觉得我们该谈谈
I really think that we should talk.
休战 不带武器 没有诡计
You know, a truce. No weapons, no tricks.
就是谈谈
Just talk.
然后我们都平安离去
Then we both walk away.
谈话 谈什么?
Talk. About what?
谈谈... 所有事
Well... everything.
我觉得我们都需要一个了结 不是吗?
I think we both could use a little closure, don't you?
必须是今天 你懂的 最好是现在
It has to be today. You know, now.
我时间很紧
I'm kind of pressed for time.
我怎么知道我能相信你?
How do I know I can trust you?
现在别这么胆小 Patrick
Ah, don't be timid now, Patrick.
有很多次我都可以杀你的 但我没有 对吧?
I could have killed you many times, and I haven't, have I?
好吧 时间地点?
Okay. When and where?
很好
Excellent.
半小时后在费利蒙公园的喷水池见
I'll be at the Fremont Park fountain in half an hour.
不行 我不知道那地方 改在中央汽车站吧
No. Don't know it. Central Bus Station.
- 北门  - 不行 人太多
- North entrance.  - Nah, there's too many people.
警察也太多
There's too many cops.
你知道Alexandria公墓吗?
You know Alexandria Cemetery?
当然知道
Of course I do.
在西门附近有个小教堂
Yeah, there's a chapel by the western gate.
那里... 可以 半小时后见
That... that'll do. Half an hour.
别迟到了 我不会等你的
Don't be late. I can't wait around.
半小时后见
Half an hour.
他怎么说?
What'd he say?
他想和我见面
He wants to meet with me.
是个陷阱
It's a trap.
可能吧
Probably.
那你打算怎么办?
Well, what are you gonna do?
我要去见他
I'm gonna meet him.
你不能去
You can't.
相信我 我知道自己在做什么
Trust me, I know what I'm doing.
Jane 别这么做 好好想想
Jane, don't do this. Think about it.
联邦调查局很快就能抓到Bertram了
The FBI is gonna get Bertram soon enough.
我不想让联邦调查局抓到他
I don't want the FBI to get him.
你知道会有这一天的
You knew this day was coming.
真的到了
It's here.
让我跟你一起去
Let me come with you.
不行 我不想让你参与此事
No, I don't want you involved.
- 参与? 我一直都在参与  - 以后不行了
- Involved? I am involved.  - Not anymore.
我需要借用你的枪
I'm gonna need to borrow your gun.
我的枪?
My gun?
没错 你的枪 我不会用的
Yes, your gun. I'm not gonna use it.
只是个道具
Just a prop.
Teresa 请相信我 相信我就好
Teresa, trust me, please. Just trust me.
谢谢
Thank you.
往那儿走了
Like that way.
谢谢
Thanks.
管事的人在哪儿? Abbott在哪儿?
Where's the man in charge here? Where is Abbott?
跪下
Get down on your knees.
把手举起来
Keep your hands where I can see them.
Abbott在哪儿? 我... 我得走了
Where is Abbott? I... I have to go.
好了 大家不要这么紧张
All right, take it down a notch, people.
他又不是黑帮教父
He's not Al Capone.
Abbott 请听我说
Abbott, please listen to me.
我看得出来你是个有荣誉感的人
I can tell that you're a man of honor.
我以我的名誉发誓 一个小时后我就会去自首
On my honor, I will give myself up in an hour.
但现在我只是... 我只...
But right now I just... I just need...
只是...
Just...
算了吧
Forget it.
不 别这样 告诉我
No. No, no, no, no. No, tell me.
起来
Come on.
别这样 你要什么? 你到底想要什么?
No, what do you need? What do you need, huh?
你要一个小时时间?
You need an hour?
做什么?
For what?
你要去哪儿?
Where are you going?
你要见谁?
Who are you gonna go meet?
不说?
No?
跟我回市区吧 好吗?
Well, let's take a trip downtown, shall we?
嘿
Hey.
不用 你可以让她进来
No. You can let her go.
嗨 Lisbon小姐
Hi, Miss Lisbon.
我们同为警察 帮我个忙 Abbott
Do me this one favor, Abbott, cop to cop.
放他走 我发誓之后就会带他回去
Let him go, and I swear I will bring him back later.
想都别想
Not happening.
我现在看到的紧急状况到底是什么?
And what is all this urgency I'm hearing here?
你和Bertram有约
Oh. You made a plan with Bertram.
是这样吗? 是不是这样?
Is that it? Is that what you did?
拜托了 Abbott
Please, Abbott.
联邦调查局! 退后!
FBI! Back it off!
- 加州调查局 你才要退后  - 怎么回事?
- CBI. Back it up yourself.  - What's this?
放他走 Abbott 他没做错任何事
Let him go, Abbott. He's done nothing wrong.
嘿 伙计们
Hey, guys.
要知道... 很高兴见到你们
You know, i... it's good to see you.
我不想扫你们的兴 但已经没有加州调查局了
I hate to bring you down, but there is no CBI.
那个警徽跟玩具无异
That badge is a toy,
你们也都在假扮执法人员
and you're all impersonating officers of the law.
随便了 放他走
Whatever. Let him go.
你们在挑衅我吗?
Are you mad-dogging me right now?
联邦调查局?
The FBI?
你说自己是合法的联邦调查局探员 我们怎么知道?
You say you're legit FBI, but how do we know?
没错 就我们所知 你也可能是布雷克组织的
Yeah, you could be members of the Blake Association
一份子
for all we know.
我们不是
We're not.
证明给我们看
Prove it.
你们的那位Reede Smith就是成员 为什么你就不可能?
Your man Reede Smith was a member. Why not you?
我们怎么知道Jane没有身处险境?
And how do we know Jane's not in danger?
这是冒犯
That's absurd.
我很抱歉 Abbott探员
I'm sorry, Agent Abbott,
但在确保他的安全之前
but it is our duty to protect this man
保护他是我们的职责
until we're assured his safety.
嘿 放他走
Hey. Let him go.
别举着枪
No, no, no, no, no.
没事的 别激动
It's all right. Just stand down.
大家别激动 不需要发生冲突 没事的
Stand down, guys. No bloodshed required. It's cool.
放他走
Let him go.
开我的车走
Take my car.
长官?
Sir?
算了
It's okay.
谢谢 伙计们!
Thank you, guys!
结束了?
We done?
他走了 结束了
He's gone. We're done.
逮捕他们
Arrest them.
慢慢把你们的枪...
Put your guns down on the ground...
放到地上
slowly.
照他说的做
Do as he says.
追踪Lisbon探员的车
Go track Agent Lisbon's vehicle.
明白 长官
Yes, Sir.
你在我的车上放了追踪器?
You put a bug on my car?
你觉得我们怎么找到Jane的?
How do you think we found Jane?
我说我很高兴见到你们
I said I was glad to see you people
是因为我知道你们会搞砸
because I knew you would screw up
这样我就会轻松了
and make my life easy.
你们也照做了
And you did just that.
谢谢
Thank you.
逮捕她
Arrest her.
走吧
Come on.
他还没准备好
He wasn't ready for it.
不
No.
哟 哟 看看!
Yo, yo, yo, yo, yo. Check it out. Whoa!
看看!
Check this out.
怎么了?
What's up?
能不能拜托你们帮我看一下车?
Uh, could you guys keep an eye on my car for me, please?
好的 我会看着的
Sure, I'll watch it.
谢谢
Thank you.
走吧
Let's go.
伙计 不客气
Yeah, man, no worries.
是啊! 哈哈哈!
Yeah! Ha ha ha ha!
你好
Hey there.
呃...
Uh...
很抱歉打扰你了 女士
sorry to bother you, ma'am.
说来话长
Uh, long story.
如果你愿意... 我想搭个顺风车
Uh, I need... I need a ride, if you're willing.
这里是第四小队 我们看到目标车辆了
This is unit 4. We have the vehicle in sight,
停在第五街和Sherman街路口
stationary on Fifth and Sherman.
隐蔽 隐蔽 他们可能在那儿会面
Stay back, stay back. This could be the meet.
怎么回事?
What the heck?
第四小队 怎么回事?
Unit 4, what's the situation?
第四小队 回话 该死
Unit 4, respond, damn it.
头儿 Lisbon车里是一群小孩
Boss, it was some kids in Lisbon's car.
Jane不见了
Jane wasn't there.
Jane不在这儿 重复 Jane不在这儿
We don't have Jane. Repeat. We don't have Jane.
听到吗...
Do you co...
别再加深自己的罪孽了
Don't dig yourself any deeper.
他去了哪儿?
Where did he go?
我不知道
I don't know.
你们还真是大义凛然 是吧?
You guys really have a death wish, don't you?
长官 我们真的不知道
Sir, we really don't know.
"长官"? 你干嘛要叫他"长官"?
"Sir"? Why the hell are you calling him "Sir"?
冷静点 头号公敌
Oh, calm down, Dillinger.
我们被逮捕了 也许应该文明点
We're under arrest here. We might as well be civil.
为什么? 你觉得这就能弄到个好牢房?
Why? You think you'll get a nicer cell?
谢谢你 Aurelio
Muchas gracias, Aurelio.
别客气 祝你好运
De nada. Buena suerte.
嘿 Patrick
Hey, Patrick.
我得搜你身 以防你带了武器
I'm gonna need to search you for weapons.
所以你可以把手举起来了
So you can go ahead, put your hands up.
总得试试
Worth a shot.
现在可以进去了
You can go in now.
嘿 Patrick
Patrick.
谢谢你这么准时
Thank you for being so punctual.
你骗了我
You lied to me.
哦... 你也骗了我
Oh. Well... as did you.
我们真是对顽皮的家伙 对吧?
What a couple of scamps we are, huh?
我保证 那是我说的最后一个谎
I promise that is the last lie that I will ever tell you.
好了... 先说重点
So...  first things first.
你和联邦调查局犯了个打错
You and the Feds have made a big mistake.
我不是红约翰
I'm not Red John.
什么?
What?
我不是红约翰
I'm not red john.
我... 很抱歉让你失望了
I... I'm sorry to disappoint you,
但我只是布雷克组织里
but I'm just a humble foot soldier
普通的一员
in the Blake Association.
红约翰是高层之一
Red John is one of the top brass.
我不确定可以相信你
I'm not sure I believe you.
好吧... 那是你的权利 但...
Well... that's your privilege, but...
但我在告诉你事实
but I am telling you the truth.
你完全得出了错误的结论
You all just jumped to the wrong conclusion.
好吧 那红约翰是谁?
Okay, so who is Red John?
我不知道
Oh, I have no idea.
我... 说的是实话
No, h... honestly.
完全不知道
No idea.
组织遵从必要的时候才会告知情报的原则
The Association works on a strictly need-to-know basis.
假设你说的是实话
Supposing what you say is true,
那我们完全能在电话里把话讲清楚
then we could have had this talk on the phone.
没错 但如果我们在电话里讲清楚了
Yeah, but if we talked on the phone,
那你... 也许就不会来跟我见面了
then you... you probably wouldn't have come to meet me,
对吧?
would you?
有人让我打电话给你
And I was told to call you,
跟你说游戏结束了 然后安排个会面
tell you the game's over, and arrange a meeting.
为什么?
Why?
为什么要我来这儿?
Why am I here?
拜托... 千万别觉得
Please... don't think for a moment
我这么做回很高兴
that I am happy about this.
组织可不喜欢有漏洞
The Association doesn't like loose ends.
他们讨厌漏洞
Just hates them.
所以...
So...
动手吧 Oscar
go on, Oscar.
别 听着 听着 我们...
No, no. Listen. Listen. Let's...
我们谈谈 就... 等一下
let's talk about this. Just... w... wait.
真的很抱歉 但我也实在没有办法
Now I am truly sorry, but it is totally out of my hands.
我一直觉得你人不错 Patrick
I always liked you, Patrick.
不 不 没必要这样
No. No. This is not necessary.
咱们别... 别...
We don't... don't...
嘿... 嘿...
H... hey...
多谢了 Oscar
Thank you, Oscar.
你到外边去等着吧...
You can wait outside. Just, uh...
确保没人打扰我们就好
make sure we're left in peace.
你好啊 Patrick
Hello, Patrick.
嗨
Hi.
嘿!
Hey!
人呢?!
Hello?!
嘿 现在算怎么回事?
Hey, what's going on?
- Grace 你干什...  - 嘿!
- Grace, what are you...  - Hey!
别... 别这样好不好
What... please don't do that.
你还不如Cho呢
You're worse than Cho.
他们有义务告诉我们现在怎么回事
They need to tell us what's going on.
他们什么义务也没有
They don't need to do anything.
而且咱们也束手无策 所以请你放轻松
And we can't do anything, so please just relax.
放轻松? 我怎么放轻松?
Relax? How can I relax?
你知道吗 我看你有时候挺享受束手无策的感觉的
You know, sometimes I think you like being helpless.
好吧 我收回 那就别放轻松 行了吧
Okay, fine, I take it back. Don't relax.
那就用你的额头撞碎玻璃
Just break the window with your forehead
咱们一起跳出去 来个百米冲刺
and we'll all jump out and make a run for it.
咱们别窝里斗 好不好?
Guys, let's try to keep it together, okay?
好 抱歉
Okay, I'm sorry.
"抱歉"
"Sorry."
Mullins 你是这儿的人吧?
Mullins, you're from here, yes?
是的 长官 就在Lincoln Heights那边
Yes, sir. Over to Lincoln Heights.
- 给我一张萨克拉门托的地图  - 是的 长官
- Get me a map of Sacramento.  - Yes, sir.
车上的电脑里有一张
There's one on the computer in the car.
我要纸制的
Paper map.
纸... 制的
Paper... map.
别愣着了 快去找
Come on. Let's go.
嘿 你有纸制地图吗?
Hey, do you have a paper map?
Patrick 终于见面了
Well, Patrick, here we are.
可怜的家伙
Poor fella.
聪明反被聪明误
Smart but dumb.
他根本没想到
It never occurred to him
布雷克组织属于我
that I am the Blake Association.
你为什么非要杀了他?
Why'd you have to kill him?
现在不是人人都觉得他是红约翰吗?
Everyone thinks he's Red John, don't they?
所以... 要是你们俩死在一块
So... it would seem a fitting end to the story
故事才合逻辑
if you two were found dead together.
没人会起疑心
No one will look any deeper.
我就这么死了?
So I'm supposed to die, am I?
都这么多年了
After all these years,
不公平吧
seems kind of unfair.
太公平了
It's totally fair.
游戏结束 我是赢家
The game's over, and I won.
这不是什么游戏
It's not a game.
有赢有输
There's a winner and a loser.
就是游戏
That's a game.
我又没答应要玩这个游戏
It's not a game I asked to play.
是没有 但你依然表现抢眼
No, but you played it very well nonetheless.
你充满着趣味和挑战 谢谢你
You were fun, challenging. Thank you.
你大概有很多问题要问我吧?
You probably have a lot of questions for me, huh?
反正我不赶时间 想问就问吧
We have time, if you want.
我没什么好问的
I have no questions.
你是个邪恶 性变态的反社会者
You're an evil, sexually perverted sociopath
可悲地幻想着成就伟大
with pathetic delusions of grandeur.
其余的不过是些细节
The rest is just details.
"邪恶 性变态的反社会者"?
"Evil, sexually perverted sociopath"?
这些我是得承认 但...
Well, I guess I have to own that, but, uh...
"幻想着成就伟大"?
"delusions of grandeur"?
没有
No.
我从不幻想
I have no delusions.
我建立了一个地下王国
I built a secret empire.
我控制着数千人的生活
I control the lives of thousands of people.
我掌有生杀大权
My word is life and death,
而且我的身份无人得知
and nobody knows who I am.
如果这还不算伟大
Now if that's not grandeur,
我不知道还能叫什么
I don't know what you call it.
我管这叫"一个卑鄙利己主义者的胡言乱语"
I'd call it the ravings of a squalid egomaniac.
瞧见没?
You see?
莫名其妙地 你... 你粗鲁 而且一脸蔑视
For no reason at all, you... you're rude and contemptuous.
这就是为什么你老婆和孩子死了
That's why your wife and kid are dead.
你算什么东西
Who are you to butt in here
在这对我指指点点?
and make obnoxious judgments about me?
你是谁?
Who are you?
嗯?
Hmm?
你是谁?
Who are you?
谁也不是
Nobody.
你过去不知道我
You didn't know me.
你现在仍不知道我
You don't know me.
你什么都不知道
You have no idea.
Pat 这就是你的问题
Here's your problem, Pat.
你是个聪明人 但你太骄傲
You're a smart man, but you are arrogant.
你想不出会有人比你聪明
You can't imagine someone smarter than you.
这也是为什么每一次
Which is why I've been ahead of you
我都先你一步
at every step along the way.
你手里拿着枪 有什么好吹嘘的?
You're holding the gun. You want to brag?
来吧 我眉头都不会皱一下
Go ahead. I'm not gonna stop you.
你还是不知道我怎么骗过你的吧?
You still don't know how I fooled you, do you?
我如何在那场爆炸幸存?
How did I survive that bomb?
我如何得知你名单上的每一个人?
How did I know all the names on your list?
原来你一直以来是缺乏他人的欣赏吗?
Is this what you've been missing? Appreciation?
嗯?
Hmm?
要不要我鼓个掌?
Do you want me to applaud?
你一头雾水吧?
You have no idea, do you?
我不知道你怎么得知嫌疑人名单的
I don't know how you got the list of suspects.
这个把戏还算有水平
That was a good trick.
但爆炸的事好说
But the bomb gag is simple.
其实有两起爆炸
There were two explosions.
第一枚炸弹仅仅只是把在场所有人震晕
The first was a concussion bomb, knocked everyone out.
而在你把我和Bertram拖离危险区之后
The second, lethal bomb that killed Haffner and Stiles
第二枚才爆炸
only went off after you dragged Bertram and me
要了Haffner和Stiles的命
out of harm's way.
正确
Correct.
假死就很容易了
Faking your own death was easy.
Brett Partridge就是布雷克组织的
Brett Partridge was Blake Association.
他的职责能够让其接触到
His job gave him access
DNA的数据库
to the primary DNA database.
他偷换了你和某具尸体的
He switched your DNA records
DNA记录
with a body that you had on ice.
调包
A surrogate.
你把尸体放在后备箱里
And you brought the body to my house
带到我家
in the trunk of your car
然后将其摆在Stiles和Haffner身边
and you put it alongside Stiles and Haffner.
非常对
Very good.
事后你真是个出色的诸葛亮
Your hindsight is 20/20.
能给你看样东西吗?
Can I show you something?
没问题
Sure.
面包屑?
Bread crumbs?
鸟
Birds.
很聪明
Very clever.
那起爆炸是个错误
The bomb was a mistake.
只是演戏
It was theater.
我知道无论真相看起来如何
I knew that whatever the truth looked like,
相反必是真理
the opposite must be true.
求你了
Please don't.
别杀我
Don't kill me.
你现在想要宽恕了?
Oh, now you want mercy?
在你的所作所为之后?
After all you've done?
你不像我
You're not like me.
你是个好人
You're a good man.
事后你会被困扰的
It'll haunt you.
我才没有犹疑
Oh, I'm not hesitating.
我只是在细细品味此时此刻
I'm just savoring the moment.
你就是红约翰
You're Red John.
我得说我有点小失望
I have to say I'm a little disappointed.
天啊!
Oh, my god!
救命! 他要杀我!
Help! Please! He's gonna kill me!
天啊!
Oh, my god!
我是警察 需要您离开
I'm a policeman, and you need to leave.
先生 无意冒犯 但你看起来不像是警察
Sir, I'm sorry, you don't look like a policeman.
我说是就是 照我说的立刻离开
Yes, I am. Just do as I say and leave right now.
- 请把枪放下  - 你得离开了
- Please put down that gun.  - You need to go.
无论发生了什么 冤冤相报何时了
Whatever's happened here, more violence is not the answer.
- 不 你不懂  - 先生 我懂的
- No, you don't understand.  - Sir, I do understand.
- 我知道您一定满腔怒火...  - 你才不懂 你该走了!
- I know how angry you must...  - No, you don't, and you have to go now!
先生 本着良知...
Sir, in all good conscience...
他从这出发的
All right, so he started out here,
然后弃车于一家小型商场
and he dumped the car here at a mini-mall.
如果是你会安排在哪里见面?
So where would you arrange a meeting?
跟高速公路之间
Someplace with easy access, in and out,
方便进出的
close to the highway.
- Ballpark  - 警力太多 那是什么地方?
- Ballpark.  - Too much security. What's that?
社区大学校园
Community college campus.
不是 是那个 那里
No, that, right there.
是Alexandria公墓
That's the Alexandria cemetery.
Jane的老婆埋葬在哪?
Where was Jane's wife buried?
- 这跟现在有什么关...  - 她埋在哪?
- What does that have to do...  - Where was she buried?
Alexandria公墓
Alexandria cemetery.
谢了
Thanks.
Alexandria公墓 出发!
Alexandria cemetery. Let's go!
天啊
Oh, my god.
哦 天啊!
Oh, no. Oh, my god!
来人啊!
Help! Please!
哪边?
Which way?
那里
Over there.
B队 搜查这边
"B" team, canvass this side.
Denyer 你跟我走 出动
Denyer, you're with me. Let's go.
出动 看他在不在这
Let's go now. Come on. Let's see if he's here.
什么声音?
What was that?
哦 天... 哦! 天啊!
Oh, my... oh! Oh, my... oh!
不!
No!
怎么回事? 我跟警方接通了
Oh! What's going on? I'm on the line with the police.
- 我就是警察 我来跟他们说  - 哦
- I am police, ma'am. Let me talk to them.  - Oh.
- 谢了 这边走?  - 呃 是的...
- Thank you. This way?  - Uh, um, yeah, well...
该死
Ah, hell.
- 这里是911 您有什么突发状况?  - 你好 女...
- 911. What's your emergency?  - Hello. Ma...
- 啊!  - 你好?
- Aah!  - Hello?
这里是911 您有什么突发状况?
911. What's your emergency?
别杀我 给我留条命吧
Please don't kill me. Let me live.
这里是911 您有什么突发状况?
911. What's your emergency?
给我... 留条命吧
Please... let me live.
我会告诉你我怎么得知你的名单的
I'll tell you how I got the names on your list.
我不在乎了
I don't care.
我... 我知道是因为我真的心理有...
I... I knew because I have real psychic...
嘘...
Shh...
接下来 你眨一次眼代表"不"
I want you to blink once for "no"
眨两次眼代表"是"
and twice for "yes."
你是否后悔杀害了我的妻子Angela
Are you sorry that you killed my wife Angela
和我的女儿Charlotte?
and my daughter Charlotte?
很好
Good.
非常好
你怕死吗?
Are you afraid to die?
很好
Good.
想都别想
Don't even think about it.
Lisbon啊...
Lisbon...
都结束了 完结了
It's over. It's done.
我只是给你报个平安
I just want you to know I'm okay.
我会想念你的
And I'm gonna miss you.
--==圣城家园SCG字幕组 http://hd.cnscg.com/==--
仅供翻译交流使用, 禁止用于商业用途
协调：有个饭团
时间轴：pisces夜
翻译：波特妹子 Red Shadow 捞小盐
校对：Red Shadow